## **NIDHIN RAMESH**

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

### **DETAILS**

#### PHONE

+65 81227664

#### **EMAIL**

nidhintbg@gmail.com

### LINKS

e-portfolio

GitHub

### SKILLS

HTML/CSS/JavaScript

 $\bullet$   $\bullet$   $\circ$   $\circ$ 

**CRM Systems** 

• • • •

**Customer Service** 

....

Microsoft Office

• • • •

Telemarketing

• • • •

Data Entry

• • • •

### **PROFILE**

I'm a highly motivated self-taught Front-end Developer with a passion for building responsive websites with HTML, CSS and JavaScript. I have prior experience in customer service and administrative roles and am currently pursuing a Business degree on a part-time basis.

### **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

## Media Search Analyst, Telus International

Singapore

Oct 2022 — Present

- Had to study and understand a set of guidelines to rate search queries for Apple Music, a client for Telus International and pass an assessment to qualify for the job.
- The data received from me in the form of these high quality relevance judgements will be used in building and improving artificial intelligence systems such as search algorithms and machine learned rankers that power the user experience for Apple Music users.

## **Customer Service Executive, Aureus Academy**

Singapore

Aug 2022 — Jan 2023

- Converted inbound prospects into customers by helping them book a free trial lesson and afterwards helped enrol said prospects, boosting outlet's enrolment rate and teacher's live teacher hours and hence helping with outlet's overall figures.
- Made outbound calls informing clients promotional packages in order to help with outlet's retention rate.
- Assisted with company's daily operations using company's CRM software (Salesforce).

## **Customer Care Officer, Ministry of Health**

Singapore

Feb 2022 — Jul 2022

- Addressed concerned members of the public and gave them advice in accordance to government protocols.
- Escalated their requests to the various departments (ICA etc.) and then liaised with these departments to make arrangements for these MOPs to mitigate the spread of COVID-19 in Singapore.

## Recruitment Telemarketer, AIA

Singapore

Dec 2021 — May 2022

- Assisted in the recruitment, hiring and interviews of potential new agents in the financial services industry.
- Mined resumes online and cold called prospects with the attractive perks and benefits of working in Financial Advisory.

# Environmental Health & Safety Assistant, Kulicke & Soffa

Singapore

Oct 2021 — Dec 2021

- Assisted the EHS department; ensuring workplace safety regulations were in place and that COVID-19 protocols were being followed by all employees.
- Involved in the designing and printing of info-graphics and precautionary statements to control and prevent the spread of COVID-19 in the workplace.

## **Data Processing & Imaging Assistant, UPS**

Singapore

Apr 2021 — Aug 2021

- Collated the data of packages that were picked up (i.e the airway bill number, value of the packages, addresses etc).
- · Had to upload this data on to the company's CMS via an android smartphone.

### **Financial Services Apprentice, Prelit Advisory**

Singapore

Dec 2020 — Dec 2020

- Had to do an individual and group based assignment on how to acquire and maintain clients if we were financial advisors ourselves.
- Gained insights and exposure into the financial services industry by interacting with agents that were already established in the industry.

## Floor Staff, Super Loco Mexican Bar & Restaurant

Singapore

Aug 2020 — Nov 2020

- · Took orders and served food and drinks.
- Witnessed the 'behind-the-scenes' operations of an F&B enterprise while also learning the importance of being a team player.

### Logistics Assistant, DHL

Singapore

Mar 2020 — Jun 2020

• Involved scanning materials using a RFID scanner and then helping to package those materials to clients.

## Data Entry Intern, Deloitte

Singapore

Nov 2015 — Dec 2015

- Job involved Microsoft office work, Excel mainly, and the saving and scanning of physical documents.
- · Learned a lot about the auditing and private banking industry.

## EDUCATION

# BSc in Business & Management, Singapore Institute of Management (SIM)

Singapore

Aug 2020 — Aug 2024

Currently pursuing.

### 'A' levels, Tampines Junior College

Singapore

2016 - 2017

### 'O' levels, St. Andrew's Secondary School

Singapore

2012 - 2015